Guide to the Consolidation Coal Company Records, 1854-1971 AIS.2011.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Associated Companies' Contract Files, VII.
  - Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company, 4.
    - Century Club, July 6, 1907-May 27, 1908; 372.
    - Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company, October 1, 1907; 374.
    - National Rivers & Harbors Congress, November 3, 1906-November 11, 1907; 376.
    - S. A. Scott, January 9, 1902; 377.
    - Thomas & William Morgan and Samuel Williams, October 26, 1907; 378.
    - P. J. Forsythe & Company, August 14, 1901; 379.
    - Pike Run Railroad Company, October 5, 1901; 380.
    - Pugh & Bloomfield, October 31, 1901; 382.
    - James Robinson, June 9, 1902; 383.
    - A. F. Johnson & W. T. Sampson, January 1902; 384.
    - Mrs. J. H. McCoy, September 21, 1906; 385.
    - Blanche & Mame Hetzel and Mrs. Belle M. Hornbake, January 25, 1906; 386.
    - PA House of Representatives Act, March 1, 1907; 387.
    - US Department of Treasury, April 23, 1902-January 30, 1911; 388.
    - A. D. Laughlin & M. P. Smith, October 24, 1905-April 20, 1906; 390.
    - John Kreiter, November 1, 1895-February 1, 1903; 391.
    - Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company, May 1903; 393.
    - J. N. O'Neil, February 22, 1904; 394.
    - Robert Wolf and Robert Lewis, July 28, 1903; 395.
    - Logan & Moulds, May 7-July 28, 1902; 396.
    - Vesta Coal Company, November 28, 1902; 397.
    - Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company, September 2, 1901; 398.
    - Taylor J. Will, August 17, 1901; 399.
    - J. M. Arnold, August 1900-January 1901; 400.
    - Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company, 1900; 401.
    - Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company, April 27-May 29, 1901; 402. (Oversize 138)
    - Harry A. Jones, March 18, 1903; 403. (Box 85)
    - Pennsylvania Lines, December 1900-February 19, 1903; 404.
    - Union Trust Company, June 1, 1901-March 26, 1903; 405.
    - D. F. Hurd, January 21, 1903; 406.
    - Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company, June 1904; 407.
    - M. J. Botun & Union Trust Company, September 15, 1903; 408.
    - J. M. Hammitt, August 4, 1903; 409.
    - Weber-Erickson Bunting Company, May 23, 1903; 410.
    - Joseph A. Moffitt, May 8, 1903; 411.
    - Pennsylvania Railroad Company, October 6, 1903; 412.
    - Iowa Iron Works Company, February 20, 1904; 413.
    - J.W. Barber, March 8, 1904; 414. (Oversize 138)
    - Mike Romain, April 11, 1904; 415. (Box 85)
    - John Shulen & Son, May 19, 1904; 416.
    - Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company, 417.
    - J. D. Le Bel, March 16, 1907; 418.
    - Chamber of Commerce of Pittsburgh, May 7, 1908-January 31, 1912; 419.
    - Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company, October 23, 1901-July 19, 1907; 420. (Oversize 139)
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File # 1476, 421. (Box 86)
    - The Saw Mill Run Coal & Supply Company, October 1, 1909; 422.
    - The Saw Mill Run Coal & Supply Company, October 1, 1909; 423.
    - Lee & Hamilton Coal Company, January 10, 1910; 424.
    - Lee & Hamilton Coal Company, October 1, 1909; 425.
    - The Corona Coal & Iron Company, February 6, 1909-April 3, 1912; 426.
    - The Baton Rouge Coal & Towing Company, September 21, 1908-April 30, 1913; 429.
    - Ascension Coal Company, September 18, 1908-May 16, 1912; 430.
    - Lee & Hamilton Coal Company, September 16, 1908-January 2, 1912; 431.
    - Nunn-Heffron Coal Company, September 18, 1908-March 31, 1910; 434.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File # 1475, 435.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File # 1470, 436.
    - The Saw Mill Run Coal & Supply Company, September 16, 1908-November 30, 1912; 438.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File #1477, 439.
    - The Pittsburgh Coal Company, October 1, 1908-January 2, 1912; 441.
    - Joseph Walton & Company, Inc., September 16, 1908-January 2, 1912; 444.
    - The Valley Supply Company, September 21, 1908-October 24, 1912; 445.
    - George W. Theiss, October 1, 1908; 446.
    - N. B. Stephens, February 28, 1910; 447.
    - Hatfield Coal Company, January 5-7, 1909; 448.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File #1532, 449.
    - John O'Neil et ux. et al. & Pittsburgh Coal Company, March 7, 1910; 548.
    - Point Pleasant Dry Dock Company, March 1, 1910; 554.
    - Celia M. Stephens, et al. & John S. McKee et al., March 14, 1910; 555.
    - Electric Light Plant, May 17, 1902-October 16, 1907; 556.
    - John Ballien, March 2, 1910; 557.
    - The Union Trust Company of Pittsburgh, March 31-April 7, 1910; 558.
    - Washington County, March 30, 1910; 559.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File #1534, 560.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File #1536, 561.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File #1535, 562.
    - Algoma Commercial Company, Ltd., June 27, 1910; 567.
    - Youghiogheny & Ohio Coal Company & The Union Trust Company, October 6, 1909-June 10, 1910; 568.
    - Peterson Brothers, April 18, 1910; 570.
    - William Ward Machinery Company, February 1910; 572.
    - W. F. Soisson & Rocks Coal & Coke Company, June 21, 1907; 573.
    - Union Trust Company (Blueprint pulled to map case 1/7/7-8), July 5, 1910; 574.
    - The Union Trust Company, May 24, 1910; 577.
    - The Union Trust Company, April 26, 1910; 578.
    - Lee & Hamilton Coal Company, August 26, 1910; 589.
    - Lee & Hamilton Coal Company, August 26, 1910; 590.
    - Pittsburgh, McKeesport & Youghiogheny Railroad Company (Blueprint pulled to map case 1/7/7-8), August 30, 1910; 596.
    - Carrie L. Miller, August 17, 1910; 597.
    - Oscar F. Barrett & John Barrett & Sons, September 22, 1910; 598.
    - Donora Water Company & Union Trust Company, January 19, 1910; 599.
    - Greensboro Gas Company & Union Trust Company, July 22, 1910; 600.
    - Annie McClure & Union Trust Company, October 15, 1910; 601.
    - Untion Trust Company, Trustee & David Pierce Estate, July 16, 1910; 602.
    - William Nelson, Jr. & Union Trust Company, July 7, 1910; 603.
    - John Nelson & Union Trust Company, July 7, 1910; 604.
    - Union Trust Company & Nella McDonald, August 10, 1910; 605.
    - Joseph A. Herron & Union Trust Company, July 7, 1910; 606.
    - Almira & Robert Hagerty & Union Trust Company, July 7, 1910; 607.
    - The Union Trust Company & Mary W. Barnes, August 3, 1910; 608.
    - B. F. McVay, October 12, 1910; 609.
    - C. M. Espy and Nunn-Heffron Coal Company, August 31, 1910; 610.
    - J. W. Butler, September 7, 1910; 611.
    - O'Neil Coal & Coke Company & Charles J. O'Connor, December 17, 1910; 612. (Oversize 139)
    - Samuel Lutz & The Union Trust Company, December 27, 1910; 613. (Box 86)
    - Monongahela Railroad Company & The Union Trust Company, December 14, 1910; 614.
    - American Surety Company & Howard, Margaret and Philips Fine, January 18, 1911; 615.
    - Marwick, Mitchell & Company, January 14, 1911; 616. (Oversize 139)
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File #1544, 617. (Box 86)
    - Pittsburgh Coal Company, October 31, 1910; 618.
    - Edward Beedle & The Union Trust Company, December 5, 1910; 619.
    - Charles V. Smith-Union Trust Company, December 5, 1910; 620.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File #1545, 621.
    - John Castor-Union Trust Company, June 22, 1910; 622.
    - Pittsburgh-Westmoreland Coal Company, December 19, 1910; 623.
    - Chamber of Commerce-US Mail, October 1910; 624.
    - Karl D. Morris, The Union Trust Company, February 1, 1911; 625.
    - Charleroi Water Company & The Union Trust Company, December 17, 1910; 626.
    - Pennsylvania Railroad Company, July 6, 1903; 628. (Box 87)
    - Charles W. Braznell & Maple Glen Coal Company, May 23, 1911; 632.
    - Vesta Coal Company, February 17, 1911; 634.
    - Betsy White et al, January 28, 1911; 635.
    - Reynolds, Harrison & McConnell, April 26, 1911; 637.
    - River Land Company and River Road Realty Company, March 18, 1911; 638.
    - James P. Little-The Union Trust Company (Pulled to OS-94), June 22, 1910; 639. (Oversize 138)
    - Mississippi Transportation Company, June 8, 1911; 641. (Box 87)
    - Kennedy Coal Company and The Union Trust Company, May 10, 1911; 642.
    - E. T. Slider, February 27, 1911; 643.
    - Frank Dinsmore and The Union Trust Company, March 23, 1911; 644.
    - T. J. Wilson, March 18, 1911; 645.
    - Emma Hurst and Bessie Schinnerrer and American Surety Company, February 10, 1911; 647.
    - D. McNeil and S. J. Jones & United Mine Workers Association, June 25, 1910; 648.
    - Annual Meeting, January 1911; 649.
    - Nugent Sand Company & K. E. Nugent, J. K. Nugent, February 27, 1911; 650.
    - Pittsburgh Coal Company of Pennsylvania & The Union Trust Company, November 6, 1907; 660.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File #1585, 661.
    - Clarkson Coal & Dock Company, April 1, 1911; 663.
    - James P. Lytle & Harry P. McClintock and The Union Trust Company, June 12, 1911; 664.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File #1586, 665.
    - H. Young, July 1, 1908; 666.
    - Lulu V. Lilley, et al, January 30, 1911; 667.
    - Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company (Blueprint pulled to map case 1/7/7-8), October 1, 1899; 669. (Oversize 138)
    - Pittsburgh-Westmoreland Coal Company, The Union Trust Company & Dunkirk Gas Coal Company (Blueprint pulled to map case 1/7/7-8), September 30, 1911; 672. (Box 87)
    - The Elizabeth Marine Ways Company and The Historical Society of Western Pennsylvania, August 11, 1911; 673.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File #1593, 674.
    - Hannah M. Neale and American Surety Company of New York, September 25, 1911; 676.
    - Nancy T. George, George H. Adams, Sadie A. Metzgar and William G. Stewart, August 11, 1911; 677.
    - Shinnston Construction Company and Equitable Surety Company, January 12, 1912; 679.
    - Huntingdon & St. Louis Towboat Company and Steaner Enterprise, March 1, 1912; 681.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File 851-D, 682.
    - National Rivers and Harbors Congress, January 16, 1912; 683.
    - United Coal Company, Union Trust Company, Pittsburgh Coal Company of Pennsylvania, September 26, 1906; 684.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File 1446, 685.
    - Pennsylvania Railroad Company & The Union Trust Company, January 23, 1912; 686.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File 1539, 687.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File 1566, 688.
    - Moved to Secretary's Contract File 1673, 689.
    - Pittsburgh & Westmoreland Coal Company, Diamond Gas Coal Company and The Union Trust Company, September 30, 1901; 690.
    - Baton Rouge Coal & Towing Company, August 26, 1914; 691.
    - Whiteman Brothers, Tug Whitewater and Tug Vanguard, December 1911; 692.
    - J. D. Barkdull, February 16, 1906-December 19, 1911; 693. (Box 88)
    - Pittsburgh Coal Company of Pennsylvania, February 22, 1911; 694.
  - Pittsburgh & Castle Shannon Railroad Company, 5.
    - Deeds, Accounts Payable, Receipts and Mortgages, 1795-1901 (Box 88)
    - Deeds and Mortgages, 1795-1901 (Oversize 140)
  - Transfer and Merger Agreements, 6.
    - Agreement of Consolidation and Merger between Pittsburgh Coal Company of Pennsylvania and The Monongahela River Consolidated Coal & Coke Company, December 24, 1915 (Box 88)
    - Articles of Merger between Pittsburgh Coal Company and Consolidation Coal Company and associated letters, November 19, 1945 – January 3, 1949
- Associated Companies' Loose Stock Certificates, 4.
  - Alabama Block Coal Company, August 18, 1898-October 5, 1903 (Box 35)
  - The Alexander Coal Company, November 13, 1900
  - Arkwright Coal Company, October 6, 1919
  - Cape Terminals, Inc., June 5, 1939
  - Cassville & Monongahela Railroad Company, June 24, 1904-May 7, 1930
  - Chartiers & Venetia Railroad Company, October 1, 1909
  - Chartiers Valley & Northern Railway Company, October 1, 1909
  - Clarksburg Fuel Company, October 6, 1903 & August 26, 1904
  - Cleveland & Fairmont Coal & Coke Company, November 22, 1899
  - Columbia Coal & Coke Company, March 29, 1900
  - Consolidation Coastwise Company, December 24, 1914
  - Dull Mercantile Company, February 23 & August 7, 1922
  - Dunlap Coal Company, January 6, 1916
  - The Elizabeth Marine Ways Company, October 15, 1896
  - Empire Coal Company, Ltd., August 1, 1934 & January 10, 1936
  - Fairmont Coal Company, January 9, 1907
  - Fairmont Coal Mining Company, January 21, 1901
  - Gaston Gas Coal Company, December 28, 1885 & February 10, 1887
  - Illinois Collieries Company (Volume 48), December 1, 1904 (Oversize 121)
  - Jamison Coal & Coke Company (Volume 48), June 29, 1942-May 5, 1950
  - Listie Mining and Manufacturing Company, March 26, 1897 & January 12, 1898 (Box 35)
  - Midland Coal Company, September 21, 1900
  - Milwaukee-Western Fuel Company, April 1, 1918
  - Monga Land Company, May 15, 1900
  - Montana Coal & Coke Company (Volume 48), August 14, 1888 (Oversize 121)
  - New Field Coke Company, November 19, 1907 & July 15, 1912 (Box 35)
  - Northern New York Coal Company, Inc., March 19, 1935-Marck 1, 1942
  - The Palatine Coal Company, December 1, 1891
  - The Pike-Floyd Coal Company, August 25, 1910-January 14, 1946
  - The Pittsburgh & Castle Shannon Railroad Company, September 30, 1871-June 18, 1903
  - Pittsburgh & Fairmont Fuel Company, May 12, 1903
  - Pittsburgh Coal Land Company, December 18, 1915 – March 28, 1923
  - Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Company, February 20, 1947
  - Pittsburgh, Fairport & North-Western Dock Company, November 9, 1915 & December 27, 1916
  - Robson & Tubbesing Fuel & Ice Company, November 1, 1909-June 2, 1911
  - Shelby Creek Coal Corporation, January 14, 1925 & October 11, 1926
  - Soo River Coal Isle Company, January 4, 1909
  - Southern Coal and Transportation Company, December 15, 1905 & May 12, 1906
  - Viropa Coal & Coke Company, October 9 & 11, 1900